WILL HOLDSWORTH

www.willholdsworth.com hello@willholdsworth.com 07903377729 4 Cygnet Close, Wixams, Bedfordshire, MK42 6FA

QUALITIES

Over a decade of B2C, B2B and B2B2C e-commerce design and marketing experience.

Extensive experience as a marketing strategist/designer with a generalist skillset including 2D,/3D design, typographic design, digital design, video editing, motion graphics, and UI/UX design.

Comfortable both self-directing projects and contributing/managing teams with a respectful and diligent work ethic.

Comprehensive experience directing internal teams and external stakeholders to deliver effective campaign strategies.

Adept at ensuring company ethos, campaign strategies and brand messaging remains consistent at a global scale.

Enthusiastic approach to creative problemsolving with an intuitive ability to learn new skills quickly.

SKILLS

- Digital Design, Typography & UI/UX
 Tools (Adobe Creative Suite Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Firefly
 Al. Adobe xD (UI/UX design tool similar
 to Figma))
- Video Production (Davinci Resolve, Adobe After Effects)
- 3D Design and Animation (Blender)
- Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, Word, PowerPoint)
- Email Marketing/Analysis (Mailchimp)
- Social Media Management/Analytics (Later.com)

EDUCATION

SEPTEMBER 2010 - JULY 2013

2:1 UPPER SECOND CLASS
BA (Hons) Illustration
The University of Portsmouth

SEPTEMBER 2009 - AUGUST 2010

DISTINCTION

Foundation Diploma in Art and Design Oaklands College St. Albans

SEPTEMBER 2002 - AUGUST 2009

A-LEVELS

Photography, Art, Psychology

10 GSCE's INCLUDING Mathematics B English BC Science BB The Hemel Hempstead School

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SENIOR MARKETING DESIGNER

FUTURE SOUND & VISION LTD NOVEMBER 2017 – PRESENT (42.5)

Responsible for generating guidelines, strategies, written, and visual content for Future Sound & Vision and its subsidiaries (Future Automation, Matthew Hill Bespoke, Shading Pro).

- Contributed to securing of over £2 million of residential and commercial contracts with clients including Harrods and Tottenham Hotspurs by creating presentations, pitch decks, and concept animations/visualisations.
- Executed comprehensive rebrand of FSV and its subsidiaries to align their creative output with target markets and wider business objectives.
- Collaborated with the wider marketing team to deliver large format artwork, marketing materials and social media strategies for two annual tradeshow stands at USA and EMEA venues, resulting in a 10% increase in new AV Dealer sign-ups.
- Maintained high quality standards across external stakeholders by creating an online resource portal containing presentations, email templates, social posts, images, videos, factory tours for external stakeholders to incorporate into their own marketing strategies.

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

IZABELLE HAMMON

JULY 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017 (37)

Created visually distinguished design/marketing materials for events, ecommerce and quarterly product releases.

- Conceptualised and created two new product range releases working closely with directors, design managers, and social media coordinators.
- Delivered a physical/digital product guide for external stakeholders for the first time.
- Increased efficiency of imaging team by directing photoshoots of products and packaging to generate templates that were simple to manipulate in postproduction.

PHOTOGRAPHER & MARKETING COORDINATOR

HARRIET KELSALL BESPOKE JEWELLERY MARCH 2014 - JULY 2017 (37.5)

Innovated at a senior level of the Marketing team producing all imagery and design work to transition to an online-focused retail experience.

- Created efficient image production pipeline to deliver 'magazine-worthy' studio and lifestyle imagery of all previous bespoke commissions in a fast-paced environment.
- Conceptualised, pitched and delivered quarterly digital and print campaigns that aligned customer age with national average engagement age.
- Executed a full rebrand of the business collaborating with external design and web-development agencies to overhaul the look and feel of the brand.

BRAND AMBASSADOR

TED BAKER

JUNE 2012 - MARCH 2014 (40)

Delivered a customer-first luxury retail experience with a focus on personalised service, product knowledge, and maintaining high visual merchandising standards.

- Acquired in-depth knowledge of new product releases during head office training events and leveraged this knowledge to design and deliver internal staff training sessions, aligning product understanding with customer needs and brand values.
- Completed an intensive internal customer interaction training program, which
 equipped me with the skills to provide exceptional customer service to both new
 and returning customers.
- Contributed to achieving sprint and stretch sales targets by upholding high visual merchandising standards, proactively informing customers about ongoing promotions, and adhering to security policies to ensure inventory accuracy.